RG 004:059, Groton Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Groton Probate Court records
1839-2004, bulk 1839-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Groton District)
74 cubic feet
Record books, 1832-1941; Probate files, 1865-2004, bulk 1865-1976.
RG004_059
2011-047, 2011-106, and 2013-054
Historical Note
Groton, New London County, Town established in May 1705, City was incorporated May 4, 1964, Parent Town: New London
The Groton Probate District was constituted May 25, 1839 from the Stonington Probate District. The Groton Probate District merged with Ledyard, North Stonington, and Stonington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Southeastern Corner Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Groton, Ledyard, North Stonington, and Stonington.
City of Groton, Probate District chronology:
May 1705 - October 1766, New London District
October 1766 - May 24, 1839, Stonington District
May 25, 1839 - January 4, 2011, Groton District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Southeastern Corner Regional District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1839-1941. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 24 for Records, Volume 17 for Journals, and Volume 3 for Bonds. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1865-2004, bulk 1865-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record Books:
Journals are numbered consecutively from 1 to 17. There are 2 volumes each of numbers 16 and 17. Each one of these numbers is "manuscript" and the other is pre-printed "order and decree" forms.
Records are numbered consecutively from 1 to 24.
Bonds are numbered consecutively from 1 to 3.
Probate Files:
Probate files are arranged as received from the probate court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accessions 2011-047 and 2013-054.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Groton
Places:
Groton (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-106, Record books, 1839-1941; and Accession 2011-047, Probate files, 1867-2004, bulk 1867-1976; and Accession 2013-054, Probate files, 1865-1975, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-20, 1839-1917, and journal, volume 1, 1839-1950, have been microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2011-106 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 31, 2011.
The probate files in accession 2011-047 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 22, 2010 (boxes 1-34) and January 31, 2011 (boxes 35-47).
The probate files in accession 2013-054 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on June 11, 2013.
Container List
- Record books, 1839-1941; 27 cubic feet (57 volumes); 2011-106
  - Probate journal and records index (Volume 1)
  - Index to probate journal (Volume 3)
  - Journal, 1839-1849 (Volume 1)
  - Journal, 1850-1859 (Volume 2)
  - Journal, 1859-1866 (Volume 3)
  - Journal, 1866-1874 (Volume 4)
  - Journal, 1874-1879 (Volume 5)
  - Journal, 1879-1883 (Volume 6)
  - Journal, 1883-1889 (Volume 7)
  - Journal, 1889-1904 (Volume 8)
  - Journal, 1889-1894 (Volume 9)
  - Journal, 1894-1899 (Volume 10)
  - Journal, 1899-1904 (Volume 11)
  - Journal, 1904-1915 (Volume 12)
  - Journal, 1904-1908 (Volume 13)
  - Journal, 1908-1912 (Volume 14)
  - Journal, 1912-1916 (Volume 15)
  - Journal, 1915-1918 (Volume 16)
  - Journal, 1915-1924 (Volume 16)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Journal, 1918-1926 (Volume 17)
  - Journal, 1924-1941 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1839-1849 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1849-1859 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1859-1866 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1866-1874 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1874-1879 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1879-1883 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1883-1886 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1886-1889 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1889-1892 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1892-1894 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1894-1897 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1897-1899 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1899-1902 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1902-1904 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1904-1907 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1907-1909 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1909-1912 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1912-1914 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1914-1915 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1915-1917 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1917-1918 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1918-1920 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1920-1922 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1920-1927 (Volume 24)
  - Bonds, 1881-1904 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1904-1920 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1920-1934 (Volume 3)
  - Probate judge records, 1849-1859 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Probate judge records, 1859-1863 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Commitments, 1892-1930 (Volume 1)
    On spine: "Probate Records"
  - Index, A-B, circa 1943-1964 (Volume 1)
  - Index, C, circa 1943-1964
  - Index, E-G, circa 1943-1964
  - Index, I-L, circa 1943-1964
  - Index, M, circa 1943-1964
  - Index, P-R, circa 1943-1964
- Probate Files, 1867-2004, bulk 1867-1976; 47 cubic feet; 2011-047
  - Probate files, 1867-2004, bulk 1867-1976 (Box 1-47)
- Probate Files, 1865-1975; 12 cubic feet; 2013-054
  - Probate files, 1865-1975 (Box 48-59)